Finding Aid for Michigan Association of Christian Churches records, 1878-1949
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Association of Christian Churches records 1878-1949
Michigan Association of Christian Churches.
1 linear foot.
851830 Ba 2
State parent organization of the Disciples of Christ; organizational records, prior to 1949, of the predecessor organization, the Michigan Christian Missionary Society.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by the Association (donor no. 3995 ) and came to the library in 1978.
No further additions to the reords are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Michigan Association of Christian Churches is the state organization for the Disciples of Christ. It was originally established as the Michigan Christian Missionary Society.
The record group consists of minutes of the board of managers of the Michigan Christian Missionary Society as well as records of the annual state convention of the denomination. In addition, there are minutes for the Northwestern Corporation, for the second and sixth district, and for the central district convention.
Subjects:
Disciples of Christ--Michigan.; Michigan Association of Christian Churches.
Contributors:
Michigan Christian Missionary Society.
- Organizational records
  - Church statistics, 1904-1906 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of the Second Missionary District, 1888-1907 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of conventions, District No. 6, Michigan Christian Missionary Association, 1891-1906 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Northwestern Corporation, 1887-1896 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Board of Managers, Michigan Christian Missionary Association, 1888-1909 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Board of Managers, Michigan Christian Missionary Society, 1929-1939 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Board of Managers, Michigan Christian Missionary Society, 1940-1946 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning the Central District Convention, 1926-1933 (Box 1)
  - Record book of state convention, Michigan Christian Missionary Association, 1878-1888 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of state convention, Michigan Christian Missionary Association, 1888-1898 (Box 1)
  - Record book of state convention, Michigan Christian Missionary Society, 1920-1924 (Box 1)
  - Records of state convention, Michigan Christian Missionary Society, 1924-1926 (Box 1)
  - Record book of state convention, Michigan Christian Missionary Society, 1926-1949 (Box 1)